<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home page on LeetCode NoteBook</title>
    <link>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home page on LeetCode NoteBook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Q600: Non-negative Integers without Consecutive Ones</title>
      <link>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/needtoknow/q600/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/needtoknow/q600/</guid>
      <description>Given a positive integer n, find the number of non-negative integers less than or equal to n, whose binary representations do NOT contain consecutive ones. Example 1: Input: 5 Output: 5 Explanation: Here are the non-negative integers &amp;lt;= 5 with their corresponding binary representations: 0 : 0 1 : 1 2 : 10 3 : 11 4 : 100 5 : 101 Among them, only integer 3 disobeys the rule (two consecutive ones) and the other 5 satisfy the rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q309: Best Time to Buy and Sell Stock with Cooldown</title>
      <link>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/needtoknow/q309/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/needtoknow/q309/</guid>
      <description>Say you have an array for which the ith element is the price of a given stock on day i. Design an algorithm to find the maximum profit. You may complete as many transactions as you like (ie, buy one and sell one share of the stock multiple times) with the following restrictions: You may not engage in multiple transactions at the same time (ie, you must sell the stock before you buy again).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q337: House Robber III</title>
      <link>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/smalltrick/q337/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/smalltrick/q337/</guid>
      <description>The thief has found himself a new place for his thievery again. There is only one entrance to this area, called the &amp;quot;root.&amp;quot; Besides the root, each house has one and only one parent house. After a tour, the smart thief realized that &amp;quot;all houses in this place forms a binary tree&amp;quot;. It will automatically contact the police if two directly-linked houses were broken into on the same night. Determine the maximum amount of money the thief can rob tonight without alerting the police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q995: Minimum Number of K Consecutive Bit Flips</title>
      <link>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/interesting/q995/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/interesting/q995/</guid>
      <description>In an array A containing only 0s and 1s, a K-bit flip consists of choosing a (contiguous) subarray of length K and simultaneously changing every 0 in the subarray to 1, and every 1 in the subarray to 0. Return the minimum number of K-bit flips required so that there is no 0 in the array. If it is not possible, return -1. Example 1: Input: A = [0,1,0], K = 1 Output: 2 Explanation: Flip A[0], then flip A[2].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangyy.github.io/lc-notebook/about/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a static site engine written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 Cobra Viper J Walter Weatherman Cast  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
